# Ryan Choi

7160 Bd Monk, Montréal, QC H4E 3J5 QUEBEC, CANADA Telephone: (438) 300-2402 Email: choi.link227@gmail.com

## **ABOUT ME**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

I'm Ryan who is Canada based software engineer with great sense and skill in full-stack web development and software architecture focusing on client's satisfaction. I am very creative and cares about design and form as much as tidy code. I like to build software that solves business problems and creates a positive experience for users, as well as having a positive business impact for the organization. I have helped dozens of companies from startup to large companies including fintech, healthcare, real estate and blockchain company.

## **EDUCATION**

Feb 2010 - Nanyang Technological University

Mar 2014 Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Information Technology

Nanyang Ave, Singapore

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Aug 2020 - Kira Core - Singapore
Oct 2021 Senior Frontend Developer - Contract

- Designed and built the Kira Frontend which is a user interface for sending and receiving KEX tokens on Kira Network and manage validators and proposals.
- Developed and launched Kira ERC20 Auction event for raising seed fund which was over 3M in just two business days.
- Developed and launched Kira LP farming platform.

# Sep 2020 - Bondly Finance – United States Jul 2021 Lead Developer - Contract

- Worked from the beginning of company as lead developer who was charged with technical side.
- Contributed to company technically to make technical decisions and make partnerships with popular companies in Defi field.
- Successfully conducted many NFT sales including BCCGXmas, Capaldi, Logan Paul using React and Shopify E-commerce.
- Developed BondSwap, Bondly Staking Platform.
- Designed, developed, and launched NFT Auction (Frontend and Smart Contract) on Ethereum mainnet.
- Tracked users' activity on NFT sales to calculate total NFTs sold and raised funds.

#### **Nov 2019 - BitGreen - United States**

**Dec 2020** Project Lead Developer - Contract

- Developed Bitgreen mobile wallet using React Native.
- Helped the team make decision to migrate to Polkadot Ecosystem and make it reality.
- Participated in developing BitGreen transaction explorer.

#### Oct 2018 - Quantum Mob – Toronto, Ontario, Canada

**Nov 2019** Senior Full Stack Developer – Contract

- Raised 150k funds for a client by automating the process of applying Tourist or Business Non-Immigrant Visa for United States.
- Bringing a novel AWS based parking system to the customer market in the transportation space using React, React Native, AWS Amplify.
- Wrote an admin dashboard which enables the super administrator and administrators access to all the payment transactions, customer information, vehicle information, units.
- Implemented real-time interaction between two mobile apps and dashboard using GraphQL subscription.

#### Jul 2017 - Equastat, LLC – Milwaukee, Wisconsin, United States

**Sep 2018** *Senior Front-End Developer, Data Visualizer - Contract* 

- Worked with the team consist of 2 data science experts and a strong python, R experts to develop a data analytical system Broad Street Project.
- Built the front-end of the platform using React and other data visualization libraries.
- Helping clients grow their business by developing and rolling out SPAs, PWAs, mobile apps, administrative dashboard and video processing.

# Oct 2014 - Softeq – Singapore, Singapore

**Jul 2017** Blockchain, IoT, Cloud Architecture, Software Development

Software Engineer (Aug 2016 – Jun 2017)

- Developed web and desktop applications to assist with daily business processes for customers and internal team.
- Participated in blockchain wallet development and writing some parts of core using C/C++.
- Architected and guided the implementation of corporate wide customer solutions.
- Partnered with Value Added Resellers and Independent Software Vendors to develop and close opportunities.

Full-Stack Engineer (Oct 2015 – Aug 2016)

- Designed and developed scalable, fault-tolerant back ends for enterprise systems, complex web applications using Node.js, Python/Django.
- Brought well-structured, sell-able product for onboarding prospective clients and potential customers while working on many projects as a Python/Django back-end developer.
- Developed IoT back-end systems that let customer's IoT fleet, optimize their workflows, and efficiently orchestrate their whole IoT system and business operations.
- Wrote dozens of mobile applications with React Native and integrated push notification service.

Software Engineer Intern (Oct 2014 – Sep 2015)

• Started software development career in Softeq, focusing on backend-end development, desktop development, interface for management of IoT devices.

# **PROJECTS**

#### - Broad Street

broadstreet.io

- Developed a data analytical and visualization platform where customers in U.S. can select/manage their preferred areas on the map, create stories, manage and share them.
- Wrote a module for customizing the selected area of the user on U.S. Map.
- Implemented data visualization in sharable cards, data & mapping tools, generating reports

## - HeyPeers Meeting

heypeers.com

- Developed a live video chat app that allows people to safely browse and join peer support conversations and meetings.
- Able to update the customers' personal preferences and needs, connect them with their peers on their personal data.
- Created for browsing, joining, scheduling easy-to-find meetings anywhere, anytime, from any devices on many topics to help customers with life challenges.

## - Digital Valet

www.godigitalvalet.com

- Wrote Serverless React Native Applications for valet and resident use which enables them check-in their vehicles, issue v-tickets, park, request vehicles, check out transactions.
- Wrote Serverless Dashboard using React and AWS Amplify for admin use which enables the super administrator and administrators access to all the transactions, customer information, vehicle information, units.

#### - Loose Lips Generator

- A project let customers upload audio files and generate face model in which the lip imitates a real person who speaks the audio.
- Developed Loose Lips Proxy Server to handle all account and dashboard functions, integrate with Stripe, handle all requests from Humanimate API.
- Used SOX for audio file conversion, Deployed on Heroku, Speech to Text Module Development
- Proposed some crucial changes to improve UX and fixed eventual consistency issues that might occur in the conversion system.

#### **SKILLS**

• Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Dart, C/C++

• Front-End: React.js, Next.js, React Native, Flutter, Vue.js, Nuxt.js

• Back-End: Node.js, Django, Flask

• Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4j, Tiger Graph

• Version Ctrl: Git, TFS, SVN, BitBucket, GitLab, GitHub

• API: GraphQL (Apollo, Relay), REST

• Server: AWS, Firebase, Heroku

• Unit Testing: Enzyme, Chai, Jest, Mocha, Jasmine

• Other: Blockchain, QT Framework, IoT, Twillio API, Payment Integration